

#### **SUMMARY**

Master degree in project management and BSc. in Chemical Engineering. Over eleven years of experience as Process and Project Engineer, Project and Package Manager developing, supervising, and leading Conceptual, Basic, and Detailed Engineering and Construction Projects for Oil & Gas industry. Over six years in Project Management roles and duties. Wide technical and leadership capabilities, teamwork orientation, administrative knowledge, and managerial skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# 2020 - Present Project Manager/Package Manager/Tender Manager, NOV, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Tender Manager for WSP, focused on LATAM and MENA regions.

Responsible for the development of the tenders. This includes:

Developing the tender to maximize Company chances of winning the project and with the best possible conditions for the following Project Execution, on time, on budget and on quality.

Managing the tender process, Managing the interfaces between different tender team functions, obtaining specialist advice when necessary, ensuring quality tender risk assessments and tender pricing, identifying potential extraordinary Risk and report such to Tender owner and Tender Process Owner (Head of Operations) for further assessment and approval.

Producing the tender document, ensuring confidential treatment of the tender, Handing over the contract to the Project Execution Manager and team.

- CO2 Dehydration Package Pecan Island Project Technip/Exxon Mobile, USA. Package Manager
- Supply of a Production Water Treatment Package required for a WTF construction project for Casabe Field belonging to Ecopetrol's VIP. Colombia, Package and Project Manager
- Supply of New Desalters and Internals for Revamping of Existing Desalters for Campana Refinery, Axion-Pan American Energy, Argentina, Package Manager

Responsible for project from basic & FEED design, detailed design, procurement, fabrication, construction, and shipment to site. As integral part of Project Team, accountable for the coordination, performance, monitoring and improvement, handover requirements, budget, schedule, quality and site safety with primary responsibility for the project.

US and Canada Projects for NOV Well Stream Processing, Project Manager

Projects including tore manifolds, desanders and tore traps business unit for sludge handling projects business market.

 Site Services Contract - Production Water Treatment Package required for a WTF construction project for Casabe Field belonging to Ecoeptrol's VIP. Colombia, Project Manager

Responsible for coordinating all the site assistance activities and vendors to provide the precommissioning, commissioning and start up assistance of the supplied PWT project, including the

aocampor90@gmail.com UAE+971 563662731

#### **RESUME**

whole electrical system (E-House, LV Busbar, Transformers) and main equipment and skids of the plant. Accountable for the coordination, performance, monitoring and improvement, handover requirements, budget, schedule, quality, and site safety with primary responsibility for the project.

Site Services Contract – Produced Water Treatment Package and Sea Water (SRU)
Treatment Package for Hokchi Paraiso Plant, Mexico, Project Manager

Responsible for taking over from project execution team, coordinating all the site assistance activities and vendors to provide the pre-commissioning, commissioning and start up assistance of the supplied PWT/SRU projects, including main equipment and skids of the plant. Accountable for the coordination, performance, monitoring and improvement, handover requirements, budget, schedule, quality, and site safety with primary responsibility for the project.

#### 2014 - 2020 Process Engineer/Project Coordinator, Worley, Bogotá, Colombia

 Master Services Agreement MSA Contract for Conceptual, Basic and Detailed Engineering of medium and high complexity projects – Ecopetrol.

Project Coordinator of Orca Development Field Project – Offshore/Workshare. Developing alternatives selection workshops applying MCDA methodology including conceptual cost estimating and high-level project assessment. Virtual team management based on Houston and Bogotá.

- Master Services Agreement MSA Contract for Conceptual and Basic Engineering for PMG Engineering Projects – FrontEra Energy.
  - Low pressure operation alternatives assessment and process optimization of gas production and treatment in La Creciente field.
- Project PSV Williams, Williams, WorleyParsons Workshare.

Process Lead. Design, analysis, and assessment and simulation using IPRSM and Aspen Flare System Analysis for existing and new relief devices of MacNew and Potter Gas Compressor Stations Expansion Project, located in Pennsylvania State, USA. More than 400 analyzed and assessed devices and systems.

 Master Services Agreement MSA Contract for Conceptual, Basic and Detailed Engineering of medium and high complexity projects – Ecopetrol.

Process Lead. Development of Conceptual, Basic and Detailed Process Engineering deliverables for Work Orders issued by Client to increase production and enhance processing facilities operation. Supporting Project Management activities in cost and man hours estimations, vendors coordination, controlling project execution and Customer Care. Some projects:

- Detailed Engineering for improving wastewater process in the Tibu Stations.
- Alternatives Selection and Conceptual Engineering to Barrancabermeja's WWTP Technological Upgrading. Workshare and Leading Houston Office Advisian Team.
- o Conceptual Engineering to Interconnect Crude Oil Plants in Cartagena's Refinery.
- Complementary Analysis for Alternatives Selection and Conceptual Engineering to Barrancabermeja's WWTP Technological Upgrading within segregated treatment. Workshare and Leading Houston Office Advisian Team.
- Basic Engineering to meet quality parameters of natural gas sent to electric generation in Tello facility.
- Basic Engineering FEED for Barrancabermeja's WWTP Technological Upgrading Project.
- Detailed Engineering for Barrancabermeja's WWTP Technological Upgrading Project.

aocampor90@gmail.com UAE+971 563662731

RESUME

 Master Services Agreement MSA Contract for Conceptual and Basic Engineering for PMG Engineering Projects – FrontEra Energy.

Process Lead. Development of Conceptual, Basic and Detailed Process Engineering deliverables for Work Orders issued by Client to increase production and enhance processing facilities operation. Conceptual capacity evaluation of Gas Plants, hydraulics calculations for production pipelines, revamping projects of crude oil and water treatment plants among others. Supporting Project Management activities in cost and man hours estimations, vendors coordination, controlling project execution and Customer Care. Some projects:

- Replacing 10 kBbl Crude Oil Storage Tank
- o Gas Plant Capacity Evaluation and Optimization
- Standardization and Revamping of gas, water and crude oil systems of Perheron Station
- Project Pre-Front and Engineering Design Feasibility Study (Phase 1), GranTierra Energy

Process conceptualization, equipment design and cost estimating for Pre-FEED stage of the PUT7 Early Processing Facility to Santana Station Project in Department of Putumayo, Colombia. Workshare with Calgary, Canada.

Project – Energy Analysis for Sucroal's Citric Acid Plant

Process simulation, equipment rating and process analysis to propose changes to improve the citric acid production process.

• Project - PT LPG Storage, Coremar.

Prefeasibility study for constructing facilities to storage 60000 barrels of LPG in the Palermo Tanks terminal. Responsible for execution of project deliverables as main equipment sizing reports, Relief system calculations including PSV's and Flare system sizing, process description and Class V cost estimate. Presentation of Prefeasibility Study Report to sponsor and key stakeholders. Meetings and workshops giving support to the customer needs. Monitoring and controlling project.

Project – OCENSA P-135

Management and Support Professional for the Contracts Administration and Control Project dependencies. Monitoring and controlling both the project and administrative performance of project contractors, insurance of project initiation documents, writing meeting minutes, monitoring, controlling and closing those identified project constraints and interfaces. Leading and supporting to legal and contract management areas during project closure phase.

 Project – Re-Engineering and Construction of Liquid Effluents Drains Systems from Esmeraldas Refinery.

Responsible for engineering designs oriented to give solutions for handling and to segregate liquid effluents produced into Ecuadorian Esmeraldas Refinery. Equipment and lines basic design, Development of engineering documents, Reports, Process Flow Diagrams, Piping and Instrumentation Diagrams, Technical Specifications, Process Descriptions and Design Basis.

aocampor90@gmail.com UAE+971 563662731

#### **RESUME**

#### 2013 - 2014 Process Department, Project Engineer, Inelectra Intl, Bogotá, Colombia – 2013

Project – Conceptual and Basic Engineering for CPE-6 block development.

Responsible for design of the new facilities for the crude and water production and process from the exploration and exploitation CPE-6 block assigned to Pacific Rubiales Energy.

 Project – Detailed Engineering of early facilities for water injection in PAD's from the CPE-6 block.

Responsible for detailed engineering development of early facilities required for handling the produced water from the exploration and exploitation CPE-6 block assigned to Pacific Rubiales Energy. Hydraulic Calculations and preparation of reports detailed calculations.

Project – Guajira's Water Treatment.

Leading Conceptual Engineering designs for water treatment produced in the gas production facilities of Chevron Petroleum Company.

# 2012 - 2013 Process Engineer and Mechanical Integrity Engineer, Escalar SAS, Bogotá, Colombia – 2012

- Project Responsible for process engineering design to Actualization of the Crude Oil Topping Unit (COTU) Instrumentation and Control System.
- Project Leader Responsible for engineering designs to Operate Crude Oil Production Tank as Off Specification Tank.
- Project Leader Bypass construction between the Interstages header and the Sweet Gas header.
- Project Leader Responsible for the Optimization of Cusiana's Crude Oil Stabilization Process.
  - Project Leader Recovery of mechanical integrity of the condensate pipelines of Process Gas Separators.
- Project Leader Estimation of corrosion rate by natural gas condensate and liquid holdup analysis in pipelines based on NACE SP0206/SP0110 and NORSOK M506 Standard Practice. Engineering Support for gas pipelines internal corrosion analysis.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Master Degree in Project Management, Universidad EAN Université du Québec à Chicoutimi, September 2016.
- Chemical Engineer, Universidad Nacional de Colombia, 2012.

#### REGISTRATION/AFFILIATIONS

- Member of American Institute of Chemical Engineers, AIChE®.
- Member of Project Management Institute, PMI®

aocampor90@gmail.com UAE+971 563662731

**RESUME** 

#### PUBLICATIONS/PRESENTATIONS

Ocampo A., Moreno B. A., Moreno T., "Kinetic Study of Methane Production by Anaerobic Digestion: Methods and Sources", Memories of XXI National Conference of Chemical Engineering Students, Ed. Universidad Nacional de Colombia, ISBN 978-958-719-892-8, Bogotá, 2011.

Ocampo A., "Diagnóstico del Sector Petrolero Colombiano: Expectativas, presente y nuevos retos", Memories of XXVI Congreso Nacional de Ingeniería Química, Energía y Desarrollo Sostenible, Ed. Colombian Association of Chemical Engineering, Barrancabermeja, 2011.

Ocampo A. Díaz J.J., "Fluidized Catalytic Cracking: Modelling, Simulation, Variables and Process Conditions Analysis", Memories XXIII National Conference of Chemical Engineering Students, Ed. Universidad EAFIT, Medellín, 2013. Recognized as the best paper.

#### SPECIFIC TECHNICAL EXPERTISE/SPECIALIST COURSES

- Specific knowledge and skills in project management methodologies, strategic management, business development, risk management, project team management and formulation, planning and projects operational control. Specific knowledge about Project Risk Management and Risk Analysis Techniques, Business Analysis, Project Planning Tools and Project Monitoring and Control techniques for.
- Specific technical knowledge about Process Design, Process simulation and Optimization using software as Aspen Plus®, Aspen HYSYS®, SuperPro Designer®, ProMax® y PipePhase®.
- Into the specific technical knowledge are highlighted courses below
  - Biomass and Biofuels International Course, Universidad Nacional de Colombia, 2007
  - o Biorefineries: Principles and Applications, Universidad Nacional de Colombia, 2010
  - o Enhanced Oil Recovery, Universidad Nacional de Colombia, 2011
  - Oil and Gas Production Facilities, Elite Training, 2013
  - o TM-3532 AVEVA Plant Diagrams P&ID Designer, AVEVA Training, 2015

#### Languajes:

- Spanish Mother Tongue
- English C1 Level Bilingual Professional Proficiency

#### **VOLUNTEERING AND SOCIAL WORK**

- Member of WorleyParsons Foundation Global Council.
- Leader of WorleyParsons Foundation Activities in Colombia supporting presence of the Centre for Affordable Water and Sanitation Technology, CAWST.

#### **RECOGNITIONS**

- Global WorleyParsons Top One Hundred Performance Recognition, WorleyParsons Recognition Plan 2017.
- US West and Latin America Services Leadership Mentoring Program Competitor 2018.

aocampor90@gmail.com UAE+971 563662731

#### **RESUME**

#### **REFERENCES**

Alejandro Páez Silva Projects Coordinator, Colombia Mobile +57 3114574050

Jaime Amaya Muñoz Senior I&C Engineer, Colombia Mobile +57 3163508622

Mariela Lahhoud Project and Engineer Manager, Colombia Mobile +57 3176549204

Nicolás Hernández Accountant – Universidad Javeriana, Colombia Mobile +57 3154978441

Juan Carlos Acosta León Project Manager, Colombia Mobile +57 3176584176

Gustavo Marcano NOV VicePresident of Business Development and Operations | LATAM and GoM, Houston Mobile +1 (281) 352 6723